<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<articles_search_results>
  <metadata>
    <search_timestamp>2025-07-17T09:41:41.798919</search_timestamp>
    <keywords_searched>Donald Trump</keywords_searched>
    <total_articles_found>100</total_articles_found>
    <keywords_string>Donald Trump</keywords_string>
    <guardian_analysis>Based on the articles provided, the general sentiment revolves around criticism and negative portrayals of Donald Trump and his administration. The overall view is unfavorable towards Trump, highlighting various controversies and actions, such as lewd acts by a former spiritual adviser, Trump's interactions with other countries, trade issues, and his administration's handling of certain situations. The general bias associated with these articles leans left/anti-Trump, focusing more on critical analysis of Trump's policies and decisions than on positive aspects.</guardian_analysis>
    <breitbart_analysis>Based on the articles provided, the sentiment behind the news articles relating to President Donald Trump are:

1. The first article seems to report positively on Trump's position regarding the need for federal intervention in Washington, D.C., to address security issues.
Bias: Leans right - as it quotes Trump advocating for federal governance to improve law and order.

2. The second article reports on ex-NFL punter Chris Kluwe's arrest at a City Council meeting in Huntington Beach, California, following a protest related to a MAGA sign. It is framed in alignment with left-leaning perspectives.
Bias: Left - The focus seems to be on Democratic Resistance to Trump's initiatives.

3. The third article covers Sen. Dick Durbin's comments on an investigation suggested by an interim U.S. Attorney regarding Chuck Schumer's remarks. There is an emphasis on political disagreement.
Bias: Neutral - It seems to provide a balanced view of political disagreements and previous statements made by both Trump and Schumer.

4. The fourth article discusses the updated gender definitions by the HHS under Trump's administration. The article conveys the policy shift and reactions from different perspectives.
Bias: Leans right - there is a positive perspective on Trump's policies regarding gender definitions.

5. The fifth article highlights Representative Don Bacon's criticism of Trump for supporting President Putin in the Ukraine conflict. The focus is on Trump's stance and its contrast with Republican senators.
Bias: Leans right - Bacon's critical view of Trump suggests a right-leaning perspective.

6. The articles focusing on President Trump's stance against the establishment are obviously biased. This bias is based on the wording, tone, and selection of events or quotes which lean towards predetermined ideas or ideologies. In this case, the bias leans right or conservative-leaning. The articles paint a picture of President Trump taking bold actions, challenging traditional norms, and facing opposition from various entities, including the media, Democrats, and certain governmental officials.

Please note that the bias classifications are subjective interpretations based on the content provided.</breitbart_analysis>
  </metadata>
  <articles>
    <article>
      <url>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/mar/13/robert-morris-trump-megachurch-pastor-charged</url>
      <title>Former Trump spiritual adviser faces charges of lewd acts with a child</title>
      <author>Michael Sainato</author>
      <date>13-03-2025</date>
      <source>The Guardian</source>
      <bias_score>-0.5</bias_score>
      <bias_analysis>The article maintains a largely neutral tone, focusing on reporting the facts surrounding the indictment of Robert Morris without inserting overtly biased language. The author provides context about Morris's past affiliations and actions, such as his involvement with Donald Trump's spiritual advisory committee and his support for a controversial bill, but does so in a straightforward manner. The language used is factual and does not employ emotionally charged or derogatory terms that would indicate a strong bias. The article's primary focus is on the legal proceedings and the implications for Morris and the church, rather than on political commentary, which keeps it within the center of the bias scale.</bias_analysis>
    </article>
    <article>
      <url>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2025/feb/28/elon-musk-federal-workers</url>
      <title>Who’s the boss in Washington? An unelected, chaotic billionaire thinks he is | Moira Donegan</title>
      <author>Moira Donegan</author>
      <date>28-02-2025</date>
      <source>The Guardian</source>
      <bias_score>-7</bias_score>
      <bias_analysis>The article exhibits a left bias through its critical and negative portrayal of Elon Musk and the Trump administration. The author uses strong language to describe Musk's actions as 'senseless,' 'chaotic,' and 'extra-constitutional,' suggesting a dismissive and alarmist tone. The article emphasizes the negative impacts of Musk's involvement in government operations, portraying it as leading to crises and devastation. Additionally, the piece highlights the incompetence and sadistic agenda of the Trump administration, further indicating a strong left-leaning perspective.</bias_analysis>
    </article>
    <article>
      <url>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/live/2025/may/23/harvard-university-international-students-donald-trump-republicans-democrats-us-politics-latest-news</url>
      <title>New Pentagon spokesperson promoted antisemitic conspiracy theory – as it happened</title>
      <author>Robert Mackey, José Olivares, Lucy Campbell and Tom Ambrose</author>
      <date>24-05-2025</date>
      <source>The Guardian</source>
      <bias_score>-5</bias_score>
      <bias_analysis>The article exhibits a left bias through its critical portrayal of the Trump administration and its actions. The language used to describe events, such as the promotion of a Pentagon spokesperson with a controversial history and the administration's legal battles, suggests a negative view of the administration's decisions and policies. The article highlights controversies and criticisms without providing a balanced perspective or counterarguments, which contributes to its left-leaning bias.</bias_analysis>
    </article>
    <article>
      <url>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2025/feb/03/starmer-leaves-brussels-with-a-tariff-free-trump-sycophancy-surplus</url>
      <title>Starmer leaves Brussels with a tariff-free Trump sycophancy surplus | John Crace</title>
      <author>John Crace</author>
      <date>03-02-2025</date>
      <source>The Guardian</source>
      <bias_score>-6</bias_score>
      <bias_analysis>The article exhibits a left bias through its use of sarcastic and dismissive language towards both Keir Starmer and Donald Trump. The author employs a mocking tone, referring to Trump in derogatory terms and portraying Starmer's actions as sycophantic and lacking in substance. The language used to describe the political situation and the characters involved is heavily laden with irony and criticism, indicating a clear negative stance towards the subjects discussed, particularly Trump and his policies.</bias_analysis>
    </article>
    <article>
      <url>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/may/18/donald-trump-is-losing-patience-with-russia-says-finnish-leader</url>
      <title>Donald Trump is losing patience with Russia, says Finnish leader</title>
      <author>Patrick Wintour in Tallinn</author>
      <date>18-05-2025</date>
      <source>The Guardian</source>
      <bias_score>1.5</bias_score>
      <bias_analysis>The article presents a narrative that is generally supportive of Donald Trump's actions and decisions regarding Russia and NATO, portraying him as taking a firm stance against Russia and advocating for increased defense spending in Europe. The language used is neutral and factual, but the overall framing of Trump's actions as decisive and necessary suggests a slight lean towards a right-leaning perspective. The article does not engage in overtly partisan language or extreme rhetoric, but it does emphasize Trump's influence and leadership in a positive light, which aligns with a lean right bias.</bias_analysis>
    </article>
    <article>
      <url>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2025/may/16/keir-starmer-immigrants-strangers-speech</url>
      <title>Digested week: Keir, immigrants have made this stranger’s life immeasurably better</title>
      <author>John Crace</author>
      <date>16-05-2025</date>
      <source>The Guardian</source>
      <bias_score>-5</bias_score>
      <bias_analysis>The article exhibits a left bias through its critical and sarcastic tone towards Keir Starmer and Donald Trump. The author uses language that is dismissive and mocking, particularly when discussing Starmer's speech on immigration and Trump's acceptance of a luxury plane. The article also highlights negative aspects of the UK boss class and the royal family, further indicating a left-leaning perspective. The choice of topics and the way they are presented suggest an underlying critique of conservative figures and policies, aligning with a left-leaning viewpoint.</bias_analysis>
    </article>
    <article>
      <url>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/mar/09/trump-pick-for-pentagon-says-selling-submarines-to-australia-would-be-crazy-if-taiwan-tensions-flare</url>
      <title>Trump pick for Pentagon says selling submarines to Australia would be ‘crazy’ if Taiwan tensions flare</title>
      <author>Ben Doherty</author>
      <date>08-03-2025</date>
      <source>The Guardian</source>
      <bias_score>0.5</bias_score>
      <bias_analysis>The article maintains a largely neutral tone, focusing on factual reporting about the Aukus agreement and its implications for US-Australia relations. The author's language is straightforward, presenting the concerns and logistical challenges without overtly favoring one side. The discussion of defense policy and submarine production is presented in a balanced manner, with an emphasis on the strategic considerations involved. The article does not use emotionally charged language or show a clear bias towards any political ideology, leaning slightly towards a factual presentation of defense policy issues.</bias_analysis>
    </article>
    <article>
      <url>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2025/jun/13/mainstream-media-trump-universities</url>
      <title>The mainstream media has enabled Trump’s war on universities | Jason Stanley</title>
      <author>Jason Stanley</author>
      <date>13-06-2025</date>
      <source>The Guardian</source>
      <bias_score>-8</bias_score>
      <bias_analysis>The article exhibits a strong left bias, as evidenced by its critical language and framing of the Trump administration and right-wing media. The author attributes the decline in confidence in higher education to a concerted effort by the mainstream media and right-wing outlets to vilify universities, suggesting a systematic campaign against leftist ideologies. The language used throughout the article, such as 'moral panic,' 'propaganda,' and 'fascism,' indicates a clear opposition to conservative perspectives and policies. The article also critiques the media's role in enabling Trump's actions, further emphasizing its left-leaning stance.</bias_analysis>
    </article>
    <article>
      <url>https://www.theguardian.com/film/2025/may/09/uk-film-industry-horror-possible-trump-tariffs-shepperton-studios</url>
      <title>‘A kick in the teeth’: UK film industry’s horror at possible Trump tariffs</title>
      <author>Jasper Jolly</author>
      <date>09-05-2025</date>
      <source>The Guardian</source>
      <bias_score>-2.5</bias_score>
      <bias_analysis>The article exhibits a lean left bias primarily through its critical portrayal of Trump's proposed tariffs on the film industry. The language used conveys a sense of alarm and concern about the potential negative impacts on the UK film industry, highlighting the uncertainty and fear among industry professionals. The article emphasizes the importance of the UK film industry to Hollywood and the potential economic consequences of the tariffs. While it presents the situation in a factual manner, the overall tone and focus on the negative aspects of Trump's actions suggest a lean left perspective.</bias_analysis>
    </article>
    <article>
      <url>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/jun/17/ice-raids-farms-hotels-trump</url>
      <title>Trump orders Ice raids on farms and hotels after pausing them days earlier</title>
      <author>Joseph Gedeon in Washington</author>
      <date>17-06-2025</date>
      <source>The Guardian</source>
      <bias_score>-6</bias_score>
      <bias_analysis>The article exhibits a left bias through its critical portrayal of Trump's immigration policies and decision-making process. The language used, such as 'whiplash reversal,' 'dysfunction,' and 'erratic pattern,' suggests a negative view of Trump's actions and administration. The article emphasizes the internal conflicts and pressures within the administration, portraying Trump's decisions as inconsistent and influenced by hardliners. Additionally, the focus on the economic impact of the raids and the mention of labor groups opposing the policies further indicate a perspective that is critical of the administration's approach to immigration enforcement.</bias_analysis>
    </article>
    <article>
      <url>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2025/feb/10/the-guardian-view-on-trumps-trade-betrayal-rhetoric-hides-trickle-down-economics-on-steroids</url>
      <title>The Guardian view on Trump’s trade betrayal: rhetoric hides trickle-down economics on steroids | Editorial</title>
      <author>Editorial</author>
      <date>10-02-2025</date>
      <source>The Guardian</source>
      <bias_score>-8</bias_score>
      <bias_analysis>The article exhibits a strong left bias, as evidenced by its critical tone and language towards Donald Trump and his policies. The author uses terms like 'smokescreen,' 'bluster,' and 'betrayal' to describe Trump's trade policies, suggesting they are deceptive and harmful. The article argues that Trump's actions are designed to benefit the wealthy at the expense of the general population, framing his policies as a continuation of 'trickle-down economics on steroids.' The piece also criticizes Trump's approach to international relations, portraying it as reckless and damaging to U.S. credibility. Overall, the language and framing indicate a clear left-leaning perspective, focusing on the negative impacts of Trump's policies and questioning his motives.</bias_analysis>
    </article>
    <article>
      <url>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/jan/28/un-aid-cuts-trump-funding</url>
      <title>UN aid agencies cut back operations after Trump’s 90-day funding suspension</title>
      <author>Julian Borger in London and Andrew Roth in Washington</author>
      <date>29-01-2025</date>
      <source>The Guardian</source>
      <bias_score>-2</bias_score>
      <bias_analysis>The article exhibits a lean left bias primarily through its critical portrayal of the Trump administration's decision to suspend foreign aid funding. The language used in the article highlights the negative impacts of the funding suspension on global humanitarian efforts, emphasizing the challenges faced by UN agencies and the potential risks to vulnerable populations. The article also contrasts the Trump administration's actions with the needs of displaced populations and the reactions of international allies, which may suggest a critical stance towards the administration's policies. However, the article maintains a factual tone and does not employ overly emotive or extreme language, which keeps it from being rated as more strongly biased.</bias_analysis>
    </article>
    <article>
      <url>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/feb/02/trump-palestine-gaza-protest-project-esther</url>
      <title>Trump threat to deport pro-Palestinian students mirrors rightwing Heritage blueprint</title>
      <author>Alice Herman</author>
      <date>02-02-2025</date>
      <source>The Guardian</source>
      <bias_score>-4</bias_score>
      <bias_analysis>The article exhibits a left bias through its critical portrayal of the Trump administration's policies and actions regarding pro-Palestinian students and the Heritage Foundation's Project Esther. The language used in the article suggests a negative view of the administration's efforts to combat antisemitism, framing them as potentially unconstitutional and repressive. The article also highlights the concerns of critics and civil rights advocates, emphasizing the potential chilling effect on political speech and the targeting of specific groups without evidence. This presentation aligns with a left-leaning perspective that is critical of right-wing policies and supportive of civil liberties and free speech.</bias_analysis>
    </article>
    <article>
      <url>https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2025/feb/23/trusted-capital-from-your-long-term-ally-australian-supers-us-trip-to-bolster-efforts-to-avoid-trumps-steel-tariffs</url>
      <title>‘Trusted capital from your long-term ally’: Australian super’s US trip to bolster efforts to avoid Trump’s steel tariffs</title>
      <author>Henry Belot</author>
      <date>23-02-2025</date>
      <source>The Guardian</source>
      <bias_score>0</bias_score>
      <bias_analysis>The article presents a straightforward report on the efforts of Australia's superannuation industry and government officials to secure an exemption from US tariffs on steel and aluminium. The language is neutral and factual, focusing on the actions and intentions of the Australian delegation and the context of their visit to the US. There is no evident bias in the presentation of information, as the article does not favor or criticize any political side or figure. The focus is on the economic and diplomatic aspects of the situation, maintaining a balanced tone throughout.</bias_analysis>
    </article>
    <article>
      <url>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/feb/03/trump-musk-plutocratic-coup</url>
      <title>Progressive Democrats accuse Trump and Musk of ‘a plutocratic coup’</title>
      <author>Joan E Greve in Washington</author>
      <date>03-02-2025</date>
      <source>The Guardian</source>
      <bias_score>-6</bias_score>
      <bias_analysis>The article exhibits a left bias through its critical portrayal of Donald Trump and Elon Musk, particularly in the context of their actions being described as a 'plutocratic coup' and a 'constitutional crisis.' The language used by the author suggests a negative view of the Trump administration's actions and decisions, framing them as dangerous and undemocratic. The focus on progressive lawmakers' reactions and concerns further emphasizes a perspective aligned with left-leaning political views.</bias_analysis>
    </article>
    <article>
      <url>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2025/jun/05/tesla-share-drop-trump-musk-feud</url>
      <title>Tesla share plunge amid Trump feud wipes $152bn off Elon Musk’s company</title>
      <author>Nick Robins-Early</author>
      <date>06-06-2025</date>
      <source>The Guardian</source>
      <bias_score>-2</bias_score>
      <bias_analysis>The article presents a negative portrayal of both Elon Musk and Donald Trump, focusing on their public feud and its financial repercussions. The language used to describe the situation, such as 'feud erupted into public view,' 'traded threats and insults,' and 'unexpected and dramatic escalation,' suggests a critical tone towards both figures. The article highlights the financial impact on Tesla and Musk's net worth, as well as the potential political and business consequences of their clash. This critical portrayal of both individuals, particularly in the context of their political affiliations and actions, suggests a lean left bias.</bias_analysis>
    </article>
    <article>
      <url>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/jun/16/israel-iran-conflict-what-we-know-so-far-explainer</url>
      <title>Explainer: what we know so far in the Israel-Iran conflict</title>
      <author>Guardian staff</author>
      <date>16-06-2025</date>
      <source>The Guardian</source>
      <bias_score>-0.5</bias_score>
      <bias_analysis>The article presents a factual account of the escalating conflict between Israel and Iran, detailing the events and responses from both sides. The language used is primarily neutral and informative, focusing on reporting the sequence of events and the statements from involved parties. There is no evident bias in the author's writing style, as the article refrains from using emotionally charged or judgmental language. The presentation is balanced, providing context and updates without favoring one side over the other. Thus, the article falls within the 'Center' range on the bias scale.</bias_analysis>
    </article>
    <article>
      <url>https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2025/mar/15/the-new-reality-dawning-in-australia-it-can-no-longer-rely-on-the-us</url>
      <title>The new reality dawning in Australia: it can no longer rely on the US</title>
      <author>Ben Doherty</author>
      <date>14-03-2025</date>
      <source>The Guardian</source>
      <bias_score>-2.5</bias_score>
      <bias_analysis>The article exhibits a lean left bias through its critical analysis of the Trump administration's approach to international relations, particularly with Australia. The language used suggests a negative view of Trump's policies, emphasizing the perceived disregard for historical alliances and the asymmetrical nature of the US-Australia relationship. The article also highlights concerns about Australia's reliance on the US and suggests a need for Australia to rethink its foreign policy strategy. The tone and choice of topics indicate a preference for a more multilateral and less US-dependent approach, which aligns with a lean left perspective.</bias_analysis>
    </article>
    <article>
      <url>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/mar/05/macron-will-make-televised-address-to-ease-french-voters-concerns-about-trump</url>
      <title>Macron warns Russian aggression ‘knows no borders’ in televised address</title>
      <author>Angelique Chrisafis in Paris</author>
      <date>05-03-2025</date>
      <source>The Guardian</source>
      <bias_score>-1.5</bias_score>
      <bias_analysis>The article presents a slightly left-leaning bias, primarily through its critical tone towards Donald Trump's policies and actions regarding the Ukraine crisis. The author emphasizes the potential negative consequences of Trump's decisions, such as the pause in US support for Ukraine and the threat of tariffs on European goods. Additionally, the article highlights Macron's efforts to address these challenges and maintain European unity, which can be seen as a subtle endorsement of his leadership in contrast to Trump's approach. However, the language used is not overly extreme, and the article provides a comprehensive overview of the geopolitical situation, keeping the bias within the 'Lean Left' range.</bias_analysis>
    </article>
    <article>
      <url>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/feb/13/trump-trans-youth-healthcare-order</url>
      <title>Judge pauses Trump’s order restricting healthcare for transgender youth</title>
      <author>Sam Levin and agencies</author>
      <date>13-02-2025</date>
      <source>The Guardian</source>
      <bias_score>-6</bias_score>
      <bias_analysis>The article exhibits a left bias through its critical portrayal of Trump's executive order and its impact on transgender youth. The language used by the author emphasizes the negative consequences of the order, highlighting the distress and harm caused to trans youth and their families. The article also frames the legal challenge as a victory for trans rights, aligning with a perspective that supports LGBTQ+ rights. The author's choice of words and focus on the detrimental effects of the policy indicate a clear bias against Trump's actions and in favor of trans healthcare access.</bias_analysis>
    </article>
    <article>
      <url>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/may/12/brazil-china-trade-lula-da-silva-trump</url>
      <title>Brazil’s president seeks ‘indestructible’ links with China amid Trump trade war</title>
      <author>Tom Phillips in Rio de Janeiro</author>
      <date>12-05-2025</date>
      <source>The Guardian</source>
      <bias_score>-2</bias_score>
      <bias_analysis>The article leans left due to its critical tone towards Donald Trump's trade policies and presidency, describing them as generating international uncertainty and being volatile. The author presents Lula's visit to China and the strengthening of ties with China as a positive move in response to Trump's actions, which are depicted negatively. The language used suggests a preference for international cooperation and criticism of Trump's approach, aligning with a left-leaning perspective.</bias_analysis>
    </article>
    <article>
      <url>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/jun/11/denmark-vote-defence-bill-us-airbases</url>
      <title>Denmark votes for defence bill giving US access to its airbases</title>
      <author>Miranda Bryant Nordic correspondent</author>
      <date>11-06-2025</date>
      <source>The Guardian</source>
      <bias_score>-0.5</bias_score>
      <bias_analysis>The article presents information about Denmark's new defense agreement with the US in a factual manner, focusing on the implications and reactions from various political figures and organizations. The language used is neutral, providing details about the agreement and the concerns raised by politicians and human rights experts without showing overt bias. The article does not employ emotionally charged language or favor one side over the other, maintaining a balanced tone throughout. Thus, it falls within the 'Center' bias category.</bias_analysis>
    </article>
    <article>
      <url>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/jun/18/british-german-and-french-foreign-ministers-plan-meeting-with-iranian-counterpart</url>
      <title>British, German and French foreign ministers plan meeting with Iranian counterpart</title>
      <author>Patrick Wintour Diplomatic editor</author>
      <date>18-06-2025</date>
      <source>The Guardian</source>
      <bias_score>-1.5</bias_score>
      <bias_analysis>The article presents a slightly left-leaning bias, primarily through its critical portrayal of the actions and statements of Donald Trump and the US in relation to the Iran situation. The language used to describe Trump's actions, such as making diplomacy harder, contrasts with the more neutral or supportive language used for European countries advocating for diplomacy and de-escalation. The article also highlights the European countries' commitment to diplomacy and their stance against externally imposed changes in Iran, which aligns with a more diplomatic and less aggressive approach typically associated with left-leaning perspectives.</bias_analysis>
    </article>
    <article>
      <url>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/jan/29/trump-media-crypto</url>
      <title>Trump Media announces plans to expand into crypto</title>
      <author>Callum Jones in New York</author>
      <date>29-01-2025</date>
      <source>The Guardian</source>
      <bias_score>2</bias_score>
      <bias_analysis>The article presents a factual report on Donald Trump's media company expanding into cryptocurrencies. The language used is neutral and informative, focusing on the business aspects of the expansion and its potential implications. However, the article does highlight potential conflicts of interest and criticism from former government ethics officials, which may suggest a slight lean towards skepticism of Trump's business ventures. The overall tone is not overtly negative or positive, but the mention of criticism and ethical concerns indicates a slight lean right bias.</bias_analysis>
    </article>
    <article>
      <url>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/feb/11/israel-will-resume-war-in-gaza-unless-all-hostages-freed-this-week-says-netanyahu</url>
      <title>Israel will resume war in Gaza unless more hostages freed this week, says Netanyahu</title>
      <author>Andrew Roth in Washington and Bethan McKernan in Jerusalem</author>
      <date>11-02-2025</date>
      <source>The Guardian</source>
      <bias_score>1.5</bias_score>
      <bias_analysis>The article presents a detailed account of the ongoing Israel-Gaza conflict, focusing on the actions and statements of key political figures such as Benjamin Netanyahu and Donald Trump. The language used is largely neutral and factual, reporting on events and statements without overt editorializing. However, the article does highlight the potential consequences of Trump's and Netanyahu's actions, such as the possible collapse of the ceasefire and the impact on diplomatic relations, which could be interpreted as slightly critical of their approaches. This subtle critique, combined with the focus on the potential negative outcomes of their strategies, suggests a slight lean towards a critical perspective, resulting in a Lean Right rating.</bias_analysis>
    </article>
    <article>
      <url>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/live/2025/jun/12/la-protests-los-angeles-california-curfew-ice-immigration-marines-national-guard-donald-trump-latest-updates</url>
      <title>Newsom says use of national guard for Ice raids ‘ends tomorrow at noon’ – as it happened</title>
      <author>Robert Mackey, Lucy Campbell, Léonie Chao-Fong, Tom Ambrose and Amy Sedghi</author>
      <date>13-06-2025</date>
      <source>The Guardian</source>
      <bias_score>-6</bias_score>
      <bias_analysis>The article exhibits a left bias through its critical portrayal of the Trump administration and its actions. The language used in the article, such as 'illegal,' 'outrageous,' and 'dictatorial,' conveys a negative tone towards Trump and his policies. The article focuses on the opposition and criticism from Democratic figures, emphasizing their perspectives and concerns while highlighting the legal challenges against Trump's decisions. This presentation style aligns with a left-leaning viewpoint, as it underscores the perceived overreach and negative impact of the administration's actions.</bias_analysis>
    </article>
    <article>
      <url>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/may/16/james-comey-investigation-8647-trump</url>
      <title>Trump accuses former FBI director of calling for his killing through coded picture</title>
      <author>Edward Helmore in New York</author>
      <date>17-05-2025</date>
      <source>The Guardian</source>
      <bias_score>0</bias_score>
      <bias_analysis>The article presents the events surrounding Trump's accusation against James Comey in a straightforward manner, providing context and background without using language that indicates a strong bias. The author explains the situation, the reactions from various parties, and the ongoing investigation without inserting personal opinions or emotive language. The focus remains on the facts and the responses from involved parties, maintaining a neutral tone throughout. This results in a balanced presentation of the events, placing the article in the center of the bias scale.</bias_analysis>
    </article>
    <article>
      <url>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/may/28/trump-pardon-power</url>
      <title>Trump is stretching his pardon power – to the delight of his Maga acolytes</title>
      <author>Rachel Leingang</author>
      <date>28-05-2025</date>
      <source>The Guardian</source>
      <bias_score>3.5</bias_score>
      <bias_analysis>The article exhibits a right bias due to its portrayal of Trump's use of pardon power as a strategic move aligned with his political interests and those of his supporters. The language used suggests approval of Trump's actions, highlighting the delight of his supporters and conservative lawmakers. The article contrasts Trump's actions with those of former President Biden, implying a double standard. The focus on Trump's alignment with political allies and the emphasis on the perceived weaponization of justice against conservatives further underscores the right-leaning perspective.</bias_analysis>
    </article>
    <article>
      <url>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/feb/28/friday-briefing-what-happened-when-keir-starmer-met-donald-trump</url>
      <title>Friday briefing: What happened when Keir Starmer met Donald Trump</title>
      <author>Nimo Omer</author>
      <date>28-02-2025</date>
      <source>The Guardian</source>
      <bias_score>-1.5</bias_score>
      <bias_analysis>The article leans slightly left due to its critical tone towards Donald Trump and the way it highlights Keir Starmer's diplomatic success in a positive light. The language used to describe Trump's actions and statements tends to be somewhat skeptical, while Starmer is portrayed as effectively managing the relationship with Trump without sycophancy. The article also emphasizes Trump's controversial remarks and actions, which aligns with a lean left perspective.</bias_analysis>
    </article>
    <article>
      <url>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/mar/01/zelenskyy-says-important-for-ukraine-to-be-heard-after-clash-with-trump</url>
      <title>Zelenskyy says US support ‘crucial’ as he lands in UK for Starmer meeting</title>
      <author>Geneva Abdul</author>
      <date>01-03-2025</date>
      <source>The Guardian</source>
      <bias_score>-1.5</bias_score>
      <bias_analysis>The article leans slightly left due to its critical tone towards Donald Trump and the diplomatic tensions between him and Volodymyr Zelenskyy. The language used to describe the situation, such as 'unprecedented public clash' and 'diplomatic meltdown,' suggests a negative portrayal of Trump's actions. Additionally, the article emphasizes the importance of U.S. support for Ukraine and the potential consequences of strained relations, which aligns with a perspective that values international cooperation and support for Ukraine. However, the article does not use overly extreme language and provides a balanced view by also highlighting the strategic importance of the U.S.-Ukraine relationship, which tempers the overall bias.</bias_analysis>
    </article>
    <article>
      <url>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/feb/03/donald-trump-cutting-funding-south-africa-land-confiscations-cyril-ramaphosa</url>
      <title>Trump says he will cut off funding to South Africa over land ‘confiscations’</title>
      <author>Rachel Savage in Johannesburg</author>
      <date>03-02-2025</date>
      <source>The Guardian</source>
      <bias_score>-1.5</bias_score>
      <bias_analysis>The article presents a factual account of events involving Donald Trump's statements and actions regarding South Africa's land policies. The author's language is mostly neutral, but there is a slight lean towards a critical perspective on Trump's intervention. This is evident in the way the article highlights the rebuttals from South African officials and the broader criticism from various groups. The article also provides context on the historical and political background of the land issue in South Africa, which may contribute to a more sympathetic portrayal of the South African government's position. Overall, the article leans slightly left due to its critical framing of Trump's actions and the inclusion of broader criticisms against him.</bias_analysis>
    </article>
    <article>
      <url>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/may/07/lock-up-the-crown-if-trump-comes-to-visit</url>
      <title>Lock up the crown if Trump comes to visit | Brief letters</title>
      <author>N/A</author>
      <date>07-05-2025</date>
      <source>The Guardian</source>
      <bias_score>-5</bias_score>
      <bias_analysis>The article exhibits a left bias through its choice of language and framing. It presents Donald Trump in a negative light, using terms like 'delusions' and suggesting mockery. The tone is dismissive and critical, particularly when discussing Trump's actions and statements. The article also includes a sarcastic suggestion about locking up the crown if Trump visits, further indicating a negative stance towards him. The overall presentation lacks neutrality and leans towards a critical view of Trump, aligning with a left-leaning perspective.</bias_analysis>
    </article>
    <article>
      <url>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2025/mar/02/usps-trump-postal-service-cuts</url>
      <title>US Postal Service faces murky future as Trump mulls dismantling institution</title>
      <author>Edward Helmore</author>
      <date>02-03-2025</date>
      <source>The Guardian</source>
      <bias_score>-2</bias_score>
      <bias_analysis>The article presents a critical view of the potential changes to the US Postal Service under Trump and Musk's influence. The language used suggests concern and skepticism about the intentions behind the proposed reforms, highlighting potential negative impacts on the USPS as a public service. The article emphasizes the historical importance and social value of the USPS, positioning it as a critical infrastructure that should be protected from privatization efforts. This framing aligns more closely with a left-leaning perspective that values public institutions and is wary of privatization.</bias_analysis>
    </article>
    <article>
      <url>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/jun/16/president-trump-administration-news-updates-today</url>
      <title>Trump news at a glance: President says of Israel-Iran conflict ‘sometimes they have to fight it out’ as G7 leaders gather</title>
      <author>Guardian staff</author>
      <date>16-06-2025</date>
      <source>The Guardian</source>
      <bias_score>-2</bias_score>
      <bias_analysis>The article exhibits a lean left bias through its critical tone towards Donald Trump's actions and statements. The language used suggests skepticism about Trump's claims and decisions, such as his confidence in achieving peace between Israel and Iran and his handling of international relations. The article also highlights criticisms from European leaders and other political figures, which further emphasizes a critical perspective on Trump's policies and leadership style. The overall presentation leans towards questioning and scrutinizing Trump's decisions, aligning with a lean left bias.</bias_analysis>
    </article>
    <article>
      <url>https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2025/feb/05/donald-trump-gaza-strip-take-over-plan-australia-reaction-albanese-coalition-ntwnfb</url>
      <title>Albanese and Coalition continue to back two-state solution despite Trump’s vow to ‘take over’ Gaza Strip</title>
      <author>Sarah Basford Canales</author>
      <date>05-02-2025</date>
      <source>The Guardian</source>
      <bias_score>-1.5</bias_score>
      <bias_analysis>The article leans left due to its critical tone towards Donald Trump's policy shift on Gaza, highlighting the potential negative implications and opposition from various Australian figures. The language used suggests skepticism about Trump's plan and emphasizes the continuity of Australia's support for a two-state solution, which contrasts with Trump's approach. The article presents the situation in a way that aligns with more progressive views on international relations and human rights, particularly in its focus on the importance of upholding international law and the potential consequences of not doing so.</bias_analysis>
    </article>
    <article>
      <url>https://www.theguardian.com/news/ng-interactive/2025/jun/01/he-is-the-strongman-who-inspired-trump-but-is-viktor-orban-losing-his-grip-on-power</url>
      <title>He is the strongman who inspired Trump – but is Viktor Orbán losing his grip on power?</title>
      <author>Ashifa Kassam and Flora Garamvolgyi in Budapest</author>
      <date>01-06-2025</date>
      <source>The Guardian</source>
      <bias_score>-6</bias_score>
      <bias_analysis>The article exhibits a left bias through its critical portrayal of Viktor Orbán and his influence on US politics, particularly the Trump administration. The language used in the article emphasizes negative aspects of Orbán's governance, such as the erosion of democracy, corruption, and human rights issues. The article also draws parallels between Orbán's Hungary and Trump's America, suggesting a negative influence on US democracy. The choice of words and the focus on the negative consequences of Orbán's policies contribute to the article's left-leaning perspective.</bias_analysis>
    </article>
    <article>
      <url>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/may/12/europe-donald-trump-ukraine-immediate-peace-talks-russia</url>
      <title>Setback for Europe after Trump insists Ukraine has ‘immediate’ peace talks with Russia</title>
      <author>Patrick Wintour Diplomatic editor</author>
      <date>12-05-2025</date>
      <source>The Guardian</source>
      <bias_score>-1.5</bias_score>
      <bias_analysis>The article leans slightly left in its presentation of the situation involving Donald Trump's insistence on immediate peace talks between Ukraine and Russia. The language used suggests a critical view of Trump's actions, indicating that his intervention has set back European plans and possibly jeopardized efforts to impose sanctions on Russia. The article highlights the pressure European leaders are placing on Trump and portrays his actions as potentially undermining diplomatic strategies. While the article does not use overtly extreme language, the framing of Trump's actions as a setback and the emphasis on European leaders' efforts to counteract his influence suggest a lean left bias.</bias_analysis>
    </article>
    <article>
      <url>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2025/mar/12/us-rules-out-tariff-exemption-for-australia-after-trump-considered-it-and-considered-against-it</url>
      <title>Anthony Albanese denounces US tariffs as ‘not a friendly act’ after Donald Trump refuses exemption for Australia</title>
      <author>Ben Doherty and Josh Butler</author>
      <date>12-03-2025</date>
      <source>The Guardian</source>
      <bias_score>-2</bias_score>
      <bias_analysis>The article exhibits a lean left bias through its critical portrayal of Donald Trump's tariff policies and their impact on Australia. The language used by the authors, such as 'entirely unjustified' and 'not a friendly act,' reflects a negative view of Trump's actions. The article emphasizes the negative consequences of the tariffs on the Australian economy and the disappointment of Australian officials, which aligns with a perspective that is critical of Trump's trade policies. However, the article does not employ overly extreme language, keeping the bias within the lean left range.</bias_analysis>
    </article>
    <article>
      <url>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/feb/07/trudeau-trump-canada-annex</url>
      <title>Trudeau says Trump is serious about wanting to annex Canada</title>
      <author>Leyland Cecco in Toronto</author>
      <date>07-02-2025</date>
      <source>The Guardian</source>
      <bias_score>-2</bias_score>
      <bias_analysis>The article exhibits a lean left bias through its critical portrayal of Donald Trump's actions and intentions towards Canada. The language used suggests skepticism and concern over Trump's motives, particularly in relation to Canada's resources and sovereignty. The article emphasizes the negative impact of Trump's threats on Canadian politics and national sentiment, highlighting a rise in patriotism and political maneuvering in response to perceived aggression. The focus on the detrimental effects of Trump's actions on the longstanding relationship between the two countries further underscores the lean left perspective.</bias_analysis>
    </article>
    <article>
      <url>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2025/mar/06/charles-barkley-calls-athletes-who-wont-visit-trumps-white-house-stupid-i-disagree</url>
      <title>Charles Barkley calls athletes who won’t visit Trump’s White House ‘stupid’. I disagree | Etan Thomas</title>
      <author>Etan Thomas</author>
      <date>06-03-2025</date>
      <source>The Guardian</source>
      <bias_score>-6</bias_score>
      <bias_analysis>The article exhibits a left bias through its critical portrayal of Donald Trump's administration and policies. The author uses strong language to describe Trump's actions, such as 'taking a blowtorch to America' and 'vilified immigrants,' which indicates a negative stance. The article also emphasizes the importance of protest and activism against Trump's policies, suggesting a perspective that aligns with progressive values. The focus on athletes speaking out against Trump further underscores this bias, as it highlights dissent against the administration's actions. Overall, the language and framing of the article suggest a clear left-leaning perspective.</bias_analysis>
    </article>
    <article>
      <url>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/feb/09/trump-musk-relationship</url>
      <title>‘They will collide eventually’: how long will the Trump-Musk relationship survive?</title>
      <author>David Smith in Washington</author>
      <date>09-02-2025</date>
      <source>The Guardian</source>
      <bias_score>-6</bias_score>
      <bias_analysis>The article exhibits a left bias through its critical portrayal of both Elon Musk and Donald Trump. The language used by the author, such as 'megalomaniacs,' 'unnerving revolution,' and 'double trouble for democracy,' suggests a negative view of their influence and actions. The article emphasizes potential negative consequences of their relationship and highlights criticisms from various commentators, presenting a predominantly critical perspective on their alliance.</bias_analysis>
    </article>
    <article>
      <url>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/jun/22/trump-falls-into-the-netanyahu-trap-israel-iran-us</url>
      <title>What a difference a week makes: Trump falls into the Netanyahu trap</title>
      <author>Andrew Roth Global affairs correspondent</author>
      <date>22-06-2025</date>
      <source>The Guardian</source>
      <bias_score>-2.5</bias_score>
      <bias_analysis>The article exhibits a lean left bias through its critical portrayal of Donald Trump's actions and decisions regarding the Middle East crisis. The language used suggests skepticism about Trump's ability to navigate the complex relationship with Israel and Benjamin Netanyahu, indicating that he has fallen into a 'trap.' The article highlights a shift from Trump's initial resistance to Netanyahu's influence to a more hawkish stance, suggesting a negative view of this change. Additionally, the article implies that Trump's actions could lead to further conflict, which aligns with a critical perspective on his foreign policy decisions.</bias_analysis>
    </article>
    <article>
      <url>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/jun/01/trump-news-at-a-glance-hegseth-warns-of-imminent-china-threat-urging-asia-to-upgrade-militaries</url>
      <title>Trump news at a glance: Hegseth warns of ‘imminent’ China threat, urging Asia to upgrade militaries</title>
      <author>Guardian staff</author>
      <date>01-06-2025</date>
      <source>The Guardian</source>
      <bias_score>-1.5</bias_score>
      <bias_analysis>The article leans slightly left due to its critical tone towards the Trump administration's policies and actions. The language used to describe Trump's tariffs, immigration policies, and energy department cuts suggests a negative view of these measures. Additionally, the mention of LGBTQ+ businesses stepping up under Trump's presidency and the framing of Bruce Springsteen's anti-Trump comments indicate a perspective that is not favorable towards Trump. However, the article does not use overly extreme language, keeping it within the 'Lean Left' range.</bias_analysis>
    </article>
    <article>
      <url>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/feb/11/eugene-vindman-trump-administration-civil-service</url>
      <title>‘Chaos’, ‘fear’ and ‘uncertainty’: US representative on Trump’s threats to civil service</title>
      <author>Joan E Greve</author>
      <date>11-02-2025</date>
      <source>The Guardian</source>
      <bias_score>-6</bias_score>
      <bias_analysis>The article exhibits a left bias through its critical portrayal of Donald Trump's administration and policies. The language used by the author, such as 'dangerous,' 'chaos,' and 'fear,' conveys a negative view of Trump's actions and their impact on the civil service and national security. The article emphasizes the detrimental effects of Trump's policies on federal workers and national security, aligning with a perspective that is critical of the Trump administration and supportive of Democratic viewpoints.</bias_analysis>
    </article>
    <article>
      <url>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/feb/12/trump-china-south-america-foreign-policy</url>
      <title>Trump’s disdain for South American allies is China’s gain</title>
      <author>Tiago Rogero, South America correspondent</author>
      <date>12-02-2025</date>
      <source>The Guardian</source>
      <bias_score>-2</bias_score>
      <bias_analysis>The article exhibits a lean left bias, primarily through its critical portrayal of Trump's policies and actions in South America. The language used to describe Trump's approach, such as 'disdain' and 'protectionist measures,' suggests a negative view of his administration's foreign policy. The article highlights the consequences of Trump's actions, such as creating a power vacuum for China to fill, and emphasizes the strategic gains made by China in the region. This framing suggests a critical stance towards Trump's policies and a sympathetic view towards the strategic maneuvers of China, aligning with a lean left perspective.</bias_analysis>
    </article>
    <article>
      <url>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/may/28/trump-qatar-plane-gift-boeing</url>
      <title>Trump laments size of ‘much too big’ airplane gifted by Qatar</title>
      <author>Lucy Campbell and Joanna Walters</author>
      <date>28-05-2025</date>
      <source>The Guardian</source>
      <bias_score>-1</bias_score>
      <bias_analysis>The article maintains a generally neutral tone but leans slightly left due to its focus on the controversy surrounding Trump's acceptance of a luxury jet from Qatar. The authors highlight criticism from both political parties, particularly emphasizing the negative reactions from prominent Democrats. The language used to describe the situation, such as 'firestorm of criticism' and 'the definition of corruption,' suggests a critical view of Trump's actions. However, the article also provides factual information about the plane and Trump's response, which balances the overall presentation.</bias_analysis>
    </article>
    <article>
      <url>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2025/feb/25/is-a-trump-backlash-on-its-way-eggs-expensive-as-ever-and-you-can-not-eat-the-culture-wars</url>
      <title>Is a Trump backlash on its way? Well, eggs are as expensive as ever – and you can’t eat the culture wars | Arwa Mahdawi</title>
      <author>Arwa Mahdawi</author>
      <date>25-02-2025</date>
      <source>The Guardian</source>
      <bias_score>-6</bias_score>
      <bias_analysis>The article exhibits a left bias through its critical and dismissive tone towards Donald Trump. The author uses language that suggests disapproval and skepticism of Trump's actions and character, such as referring to him as not a king or god, and highlighting his failures and controversies. The article also emphasizes negative polling data and public disillusionment, framing these as signs of a potential backlash against Trump. The choice of words and the focus on Trump's perceived shortcomings contribute to a narrative that is unfavorable to him, aligning with a left-leaning perspective.</bias_analysis>
    </article>
    <article>
      <url>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/may/21/trump-south-africa-cyril-ramaphosa</url>
      <title>Sinister Trump dims the lights for another White House ambush</title>
      <author>David Smith in Washington</author>
      <date>21-05-2025</date>
      <source>The Guardian</source>
      <bias_score>-6</bias_score>
      <bias_analysis>The article exhibits a left bias through its critical and mocking tone towards Donald Trump. The author uses language that portrays Trump in a negative light, comparing him to a Bond villain and describing his actions as sinister and delusional. The article emphasizes Trump's controversial past and his alleged attempts to intimidate and ambush the South African president, Cyril Ramaphosa. The choice of words and the framing of events suggest a dismissive and critical stance towards Trump, aligning with a left-leaning perspective.</bias_analysis>
    </article>
    <article>
      <url>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2025/may/13/us-inflation-trump-tariffs</url>
      <title>US monthly inflation rate slows amid Trump tariffs</title>
      <author>Lauren Aratani in New York</author>
      <date>13-05-2025</date>
      <source>The Guardian</source>
      <bias_score>-1.5</bias_score>
      <bias_analysis>The article leans slightly left due to its focus on economic anxiety under Trump's administration and the potential negative impacts of his tariff policies. The author highlights consumer pessimism and economic uncertainty, which could be interpreted as a critique of Trump's economic strategies. However, the language is not overly extreme or dismissive, and the article provides factual information about inflation rates and economic indicators.</bias_analysis>
    </article>
    <article>
      <url>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/feb/04/rfk-jr-senate-committee-vote</url>
      <title>RFK Jr clears crucial Senate panel vote to advance HHS secretary nomination</title>
      <author>Joan E Greve in Washington</author>
      <date>04-02-2025</date>
      <source>The Guardian</source>
      <bias_score>-2</bias_score>
      <bias_analysis>The article leans left due to its critical tone towards Robert F Kennedy Jr.'s nomination and the Republican support for it. The author highlights the controversy surrounding Kennedy, particularly focusing on his past comments about vaccines and potential conflicts of interest. The language used suggests skepticism about Kennedy's ability to lead the Department of Health and Human Services effectively, and it emphasizes Democratic opposition and concerns about his confirmation. The article presents a narrative that aligns with Democratic viewpoints, particularly in its portrayal of Kennedy as a threat to public health and its focus on the potential negative implications of his nomination.</bias_analysis>
    </article>
    <article>
      <url>https://www.breitbart.com/politics/2025/02/19/report-trump-suggests-federal-government-take-govern-washington-d-c/</url>
      <title>Report: Trump Suggests Federal Government ‘Take Over,’ ‘Govern’ D.C.</title>
      <author>Elizabeth Weibel</author>
      <date>19-02-2025</date>
      <source>Breitbart News Network</source>
      <bias_score>3</bias_score>
      <bias_analysis>The article presents a right-leaning bias, primarily due to its focus on Trump's perspective and proposals regarding the governance of Washington, D.C. The language used in the article does not critically analyze or challenge Trump's statements, instead, it highlights his views on crime and governance in D.C. The article also references crime statistics and budget changes in a manner that aligns with Trump's narrative, without offering a counterbalance or alternative perspectives. This presentation style suggests a favorable view of Trump's approach, indicative of a right-leaning bias.</bias_analysis>
    </article>
    <article>
      <url>https://www.breitbart.com/sports/2025/02/19/former-nfl-punter-chris-kluwe-arrested-after-protesting-maga-plaque-at-california-city-council-meeting/</url>
      <title>Former NFL Punter Chris Kluwe Arrested After Protesting ‘MAGA Plaque’ at California City Council Meeting</title>
      <author>Dylan Gwinn</author>
      <date>19-02-2025</date>
      <source>Breitbart News Network</source>
      <bias_score>-6</bias_score>
      <bias_analysis>The article exhibits a left bias through its portrayal of Chris Kluwe's protest against a MAGA sign. The language used to describe Kluwe's actions, such as 'prolonged rant' and 'linked MAGA supporters to Nazis,' suggests a dismissive tone towards the MAGA movement and aligns with left-wing perspectives. Additionally, the article highlights Kluwe's history of supporting left-wing causes, reinforcing the bias by framing his actions as part of a broader ideological stance.</bias_analysis>
    </article>
    <article>
      <url>https://www.breitbart.com/clips/2025/02/19/durbin-schumer-telling-scotus-it-will-pay-the-price-wasnt-a-threat-trump-has-unleashed-threats/</url>
      <title>Durbin: Schumer Telling SCOTUS It Will ‘Pay the Price’ Wasn’t a Threat, Trump ‘Has Unleashed Threats’</title>
      <author>Ian Hanchett</author>
      <date>19-02-2025</date>
      <source>Breitbart News Network</source>
      <bias_score>-2</bias_score>
      <bias_analysis>The article leans left due to its framing of the situation involving Chuck Schumer and the Supreme Court as a political disagreement rather than a threat. The author highlights the perspective of a Democratic senator and contrasts it with the actions of the Trump administration, suggesting a pattern of threats from Trump. The language used does not employ extreme or inflammatory terms, but the focus on criticizing Trump's behavior while downplaying Schumer's comments indicates a lean left bias.</bias_analysis>
    </article>
    <article>
      <url>https://www.breitbart.com/politics/2025/02/19/hhs-releases-guidance-gender-definitions-recognizes-two-genders/</url>
      <title>HHS Releases Guidance on Gender Definitions, Recognizes Two Genders</title>
      <author>Elizabeth Weibel</author>
      <date>19-02-2025</date>
      <source>Breitbart News Network</source>
      <bias_score>3</bias_score>
      <bias_analysis>The article has a right bias due to its presentation of the HHS guidance and executive orders in a positive light, aligning with conservative views on gender. The language used in the article supports the notion of 'restoring biological truth' and 'common sense,' which are phrases often associated with conservative rhetoric. The article does not present any counterarguments or perspectives, focusing solely on the actions and statements of the current administration, which further indicates a right-leaning bias.</bias_analysis>
    </article>
    <article>
      <url>https://www.breitbart.com/clips/2025/02/19/gop-rep-bacon-trump-is-wrong-on-ukraine-he-needs-a-do-over-day/</url>
      <title>GOP Rep. Bacon: Trump Is ‘Wrong’ on Ukraine, He ‘Needs a Do-Over Day’</title>
      <author>Pam Key</author>
      <date>19-02-2025</date>
      <source>Breitbart News Network</source>
      <bias_score>1.5</bias_score>
      <bias_analysis>The article leans right due to its critical stance on President Trump's position regarding the Ukraine conflict, as expressed by GOP Representative Don Bacon. The language used by the author highlights Bacon's disagreement with Trump and emphasizes the need for moral clarity, which aligns with a more traditional conservative viewpoint that supports Ukraine against Russian aggression. The article does not use extreme language but presents a perspective that is critical of Trump's approach while advocating for a stronger stance in support of Ukraine, which is consistent with a right-leaning perspective.</bias_analysis>
    </article>
    <article>
      <url>https://www.breitbart.com/clips/2025/02/19/waltz-those-who-wanted-gaza-ceasefire-now-bashing-how-we-get-to-one-in-europe/</url>
      <title>Waltz: Those Who Wanted Gaza Ceasefire Now Bashing How We Get to One in Europe</title>
      <author>Ian Hanchett</author>
      <date>19-02-2025</date>
      <source>Breitbart News Network</source>
      <bias_score>2</bias_score>
      <bias_analysis>The article leans right due to its positive portrayal of the Trump administration's strategy in achieving peace in Europe. The author presents the administration's approach as effective and necessary, while dismissing criticism from those who previously demanded a ceasefire in other regions. The language used suggests a favorable view of Trump's leadership and decision-making capabilities, which aligns with a right-leaning perspective.</bias_analysis>
    </article>
    <article>
      <url>https://www.breitbart.com/politics/2025/02/19/trump-floats-giving-20-of-savings-from-doge-to-american-citizens/</url>
      <title>Trump Floats Giving 20% of Savings from DOGE ‘To American Citizens’</title>
      <author>Elizabeth Weibel</author>
      <date>19-02-2025</date>
      <source>Breitbart News Network</source>
      <bias_score>2</bias_score>
      <bias_analysis>The article presents a positive portrayal of Donald Trump and his administration's efforts, particularly highlighting the accomplishments of the Department of Government Efficiency (DOGE) under Elon Musk's leadership. The language used is favorable towards Trump, emphasizing achievements such as curbing inflation and saving taxpayer money. The article also discusses potential benefits for American citizens, such as the proposed 'DOGE Dividend,' in a manner that suggests approval of these initiatives. Overall, the tone and presentation suggest a lean right bias, as it aligns with conservative values of fiscal responsibility and government efficiency.</bias_analysis>
    </article>
    <article>
      <url>https://www.breitbart.com/clips/2025/02/19/thune-ukraine-european-allies-will-have-to-be-brought-in-on-negotiations/</url>
      <title>Thune: Ukraine, European Allies Will Have to Be Brought In on Negotiations</title>
      <author/>
      <date>19-02-2025</date>
      <source>Breitbart News Network</source>
      <bias_score>1.5</bias_score>
      <bias_analysis>The article presents a relatively neutral account of John Thune's comments on the Russia-Ukraine negotiations, focusing on the necessity of involving Ukraine and European allies in the process. The language used by the author is straightforward and lacks any overtly biased or emotionally charged terms. However, the context of the discussion, which involves criticism of President Trump and the portrayal of the negotiation dynamics, suggests a slight lean towards a right perspective. This is due to the emphasis on the need for a peaceful resolution and the acknowledgment of the complexities involved in the negotiations, which aligns with a more conservative viewpoint on international diplomacy.</bias_analysis>
    </article>
    <article>
      <url>https://www.breitbart.com/clips/2025/02/19/tim-scott-first-time-in-my-time-in-washington-republicans-playing-team-ball/</url>
      <title>Tim Scott: ‘First Time in My Time in Washington, Republicans Playing Team Ball’</title>
      <author/>
      <date>19-02-2025</date>
      <source>Breitbart News Network</source>
      <bias_score>1.5</bias_score>
      <bias_analysis>The article presents a positive view of the Republican Party's unity and cooperation, particularly highlighting the collaboration among key figures like Tim Scott, John Thune, and Donald Trump. The language used is supportive of the Republican efforts to pass significant legislation, emphasizing teamwork and alignment with President Trump's priorities. The article does not critique or question the Republican strategies or policies, which suggests a lean right bias in its presentation.</bias_analysis>
    </article>
    <article>
      <url>https://www.breitbart.com/clips/2025/02/19/cnns-tapper-trump-breaking-with-truth-basic-decency/</url>
      <title>CNN’s Tapper: Trump Breaking with ‘Truth,’ ‘Basic Decency’</title>
      <author/>
      <date>19-02-2025</date>
      <source>Breitbart News Network</source>
      <bias_score>-6</bias_score>
      <bias_analysis>The article exhibits a left bias through its critical tone towards President Trump. The language used by the author, such as 'breaking with truth' and 'basic decency,' conveys a negative portrayal of Trump's actions and statements. The article emphasizes Trump's alleged falsehoods and contrasts them with the actions of other political figures, suggesting a disapproval of his approach. The focus on Trump's perceived deviation from norms and facts further underscores the critical stance taken by the author.</bias_analysis>
    </article>
    <article>
      <url>https://www.breitbart.com/economy/2025/02/19/watch-live-donald-trump-speaks-at-economic-summit/</url>
      <title>Watch Live: Donald Trump Speaks at Economic Summit</title>
      <author>Breitbart News</author>
      <date>19-02-2025</date>
      <source>Breitbart News Network</source>
      <bias_score>3</bias_score>
      <bias_analysis>The article has a right bias due to its positive portrayal of Donald Trump and his participation in the economic summit. The language used is favorable, highlighting Trump's efforts to 'jumpstart America’s New Golden Age' and 'supercharging economic growth and prosperity.' The article presents Trump in a positive light, focusing on his leadership and economic initiatives without offering any critical perspective or alternative viewpoints.</bias_analysis>
    </article>
    <article>
      <url>https://www.breitbart.com/asia/2025/02/19/china-condemns-trumps-tariff-shocks-at-world-trade-organization-meeting/</url>
      <title>China Condemns Trump’s ‘Tariff Shocks’ at World Trade Organization Meeting</title>
      <author>John Hayward</author>
      <date>19-02-2025</date>
      <source>Breitbart News Network</source>
      <bias_score>2</bias_score>
      <bias_analysis>The article presents a perspective that is critical of China and supportive of Trump's trade policies. The language used to describe China's actions and status, such as 'absurdly classifying itself as a developing nation' and 'predatory non-market economic system,' indicates a bias against China. The article also highlights the U.S. perspective on trade issues and Trump's skepticism of international organizations, portraying these actions in a somewhat positive light. This suggests a lean right bias, as it aligns with conservative viewpoints on trade and international relations.</bias_analysis>
    </article>
    <article>
      <url>https://www.breitbart.com/clips/2025/02/19/behar-fox-news-should-have-played-trump-musk-interview-on-valentines-day/</url>
      <title>Behar: Fox News Should Have Played Trump, Musk Interview ‘On Valentine’s Day’</title>
      <author>Pam Key</author>
      <date>19-02-2025</date>
      <source>Breitbart News Network</source>
      <bias_score>-4</bias_score>
      <bias_analysis>The article exhibits a left bias through its sarcastic and dismissive tone towards Donald Trump and Elon Musk. The author's choice of words and framing, such as suggesting the interview should have aired on 'Valentine's Day' and referring to the situation as a 'happy couple' in a 'Bachelor D.C. edition,' implies a mocking attitude. The article also highlights negative comments from Steve Bannon, which further emphasizes the critical stance towards the subjects involved.</bias_analysis>
    </article>
    <article>
      <url>https://www.breitbart.com/politics/2025/02/19/exclusive-senate-leaders-plow-through-confirmations-of-trumps-cabinet-surpassing-pace-of-obama-in-2009/</url>
      <title>Exclusive: Senate Leaders Plow Through Confirmations of Trump’s Cabinet, Surpassing Pace of Obama in 2009</title>
      <author>Matthew Boyle</author>
      <date>19-02-2025</date>
      <source>Breitbart News Network</source>
      <bias_score>3</bias_score>
      <bias_analysis>The article exhibits a right bias due to its positive framing of the Senate Republicans' actions in confirming Trump's cabinet members. The language used highlights the efficiency and success of the Republican-led Senate in comparison to previous Democratic administrations, emphasizing the speed and effectiveness of their confirmations. The article also contrasts the Republican achievements with the perceived obstruction by Democrats, further reinforcing a right-leaning perspective.</bias_analysis>
    </article>
    <article>
      <url>https://www.breitbart.com/politics/2025/02/19/trump-posts-strong-approval-ratings-after-busy-first-month/</url>
      <title>Trump Posts Strong Approval Ratings After Busy First Month</title>
      <author>Nick Gilbertson</author>
      <date>19-02-2025</date>
      <source>Breitbart News Network</source>
      <bias_score>1.5</bias_score>
      <bias_analysis>The article presents information about Donald Trump's approval ratings in a factual manner, focusing on data from various polls. The language used is neutral and does not include emotionally charged or biased terms. However, the selection of polls and the emphasis on Trump's improved ratings compared to his first term could suggest a slight lean towards a positive portrayal of Trump, which aligns with a lean right bias. The article does not critique or provide context beyond the polling data, which contributes to its overall neutral to slightly right-leaning presentation.</bias_analysis>
    </article>
    <article>
      <url>https://www.breitbart.com/politics/2025/02/19/nolte-far-left-target-stores-face-backlash-after-dei-retreat/</url>
      <title>Nolte: Far-Left Target Stores Face Backlash After DEI Retreat</title>
      <author>John Nolte</author>
      <date>19-02-2025</date>
      <source>Breitbart News Network</source>
      <bias_score>7</bias_score>
      <bias_analysis>The article exhibits a strong right bias, as evidenced by the use of derogatory language and pejorative terms such as 'far-left,' 'groomers,' and 'fascist' to describe Target and its DEI initiatives. The author expresses clear disdain for leftist policies and celebrates the backlash against Target's DEI programs, framing it as a victory for 'Normal People.' The language is emotionally charged and dismissive of diversity and inclusion efforts, which aligns with a right-leaning perspective. The article lacks a balanced presentation and instead focuses on ridiculing and criticizing leftist ideologies.</bias_analysis>
    </article>
    <article>
      <url>https://www.breitbart.com/politics/2025/02/19/peter-schweizer-k-street-overdrive-trying-halt-trump-reforms/</url>
      <title>Peter Schweizer: K Street Is in Overdrive Trying to Halt Trump’s Big Changes</title>
      <author>Breitbart News</author>
      <date>19-02-2025</date>
      <source>Breitbart News Network</source>
      <bias_score>3.5</bias_score>
      <bias_analysis>The article exhibits a right bias due to its focus on portraying Trump's administration and its reform efforts in a positive light, particularly in contrast to the lobbying activities of institutions like Harvard and foreign governments. The language used emphasizes the resistance faced by Trump's agenda from powerful lobbying firms, suggesting a battle against entrenched interests. The article highlights the involvement of Trump loyalists in lobbying firms as a strategic advantage, which aligns with a pro-Trump narrative. The overall tone and presentation of the information suggest a favorable view of Trump's policies and a critical stance towards the opposition from lobbying entities.</bias_analysis>
    </article>
    <article>
      <url>https://www.breitbart.com/politics/2025/02/19/nolte-musk-floats-idea-of-taxpayer-rebate-checks-based-on-doge-savings/</url>
      <title>Nolte: Musk Floats Idea of Taxpayer Rebate Checks Based on DOGE Savings</title>
      <author>John Nolte</author>
      <date>19-02-2025</date>
      <source>Breitbart News Network</source>
      <bias_score>4</bias_score>
      <bias_analysis>The article exhibits a right bias through its positive portrayal of Elon Musk and Donald Trump, as well as its critical stance towards Democrats and the media. The language used is supportive of the proposed rebate idea and dismissive of opposition, describing Democrats and media allies in a negative light. The author's tone is enthusiastic about the proposal and the actions of Trump and Musk, while portraying their opponents as ineffective and desperate. This aligns with a right-leaning perspective that favors conservative figures and policies.</bias_analysis>
    </article>
    <article>
      <url>https://www.breitbart.com/latin-america/2025/02/19/honduras-renews-extradition-treaty-with-the-u-s-it-dumped-during-biden-era/</url>
      <title>Honduras Renews Extradition Treaty with the U.S. It Dumped During Biden Era</title>
      <author>Christian K. Caruzo</author>
      <date>19-02-2025</date>
      <source>Breitbart News Network</source>
      <bias_score>3</bias_score>
      <bias_analysis>The article exhibits a right bias through its portrayal of the political dynamics between Honduras and the United States. The author uses terms such as 'far-left' to describe the Honduran president, which can indicate a negative connotation towards left-leaning politics. The article also highlights the positive interactions between Honduras and the Trump administration, while framing the Biden administration's actions as interference. The language and focus suggest a preference for conservative policies and figures, aligning with a right-leaning perspective.</bias_analysis>
    </article>
    <article>
      <url>https://www.breitbart.com/politics/2025/02/19/nolte-media-concerned-zelensky-could-lose-if-he-holds-elections/</url>
      <title>Nolte: Media Concerned Zelensky Could Lose If He Holds Elections</title>
      <author>John Nolte</author>
      <date>19-02-2025</date>
      <source>Breitbart News Network</source>
      <bias_score>3.5</bias_score>
      <bias_analysis>The article exhibits a right bias, primarily through its critical stance on Zelensky and the portrayal of Trump's actions as logical and strategic. The language used to describe the situation is dismissive of Zelensky's decisions, such as canceling elections and declaring martial law, while emphasizing the futility of the war and the financial burden on the U.S. The author also questions the legitimacy of Zelensky's presidency without elections and criticizes the 'establishment' for supporting the ongoing conflict. The overall tone suggests a preference for ending the war through negotiation, even if it means conceding territory to Russia, which aligns with a right-leaning perspective that prioritizes reducing U.S. involvement in foreign conflicts.</bias_analysis>
    </article>
    <article>
      <url>https://www.breitbart.com/politics/2025/02/19/kennedy-center-cancels-gay-mens-chorus-lgbtqia-pride-performance/</url>
      <title>Kennedy Center Cancels Gay Men’s Chorus LGBTQIA+ Pride Performance</title>
      <author>Olivia Rondeau</author>
      <date>19-02-2025</date>
      <source>Breitbart News Network</source>
      <bias_score>3</bias_score>
      <bias_analysis>The article exhibits a right bias through its presentation and framing of the events. The focus on President Trump's actions and decisions at the Kennedy Center, particularly the cancellation of the LGBTQIA+ Pride performance, is presented in a manner that aligns with conservative values. The article highlights Trump's influence and decisions without providing a balanced perspective or counterarguments, which could suggest an endorsement of his actions. Additionally, the language used to describe the Kennedy Center's previous events and the emphasis on Trump's statements further indicate a right-leaning perspective.</bias_analysis>
    </article>
    <article>
      <url>https://www.breitbart.com/middle-east/2025/02/19/zelensky-cancels-saudi-arabia-trip-after-exclusion-from-u-s-russia-talks/</url>
      <title>Zelensky Cancels Saudi Arabia Trip After Exclusion from U.S.-Russia Talks</title>
      <author>John Hayward</author>
      <date>19-02-2025</date>
      <source>Breitbart News Network</source>
      <bias_score>1.5</bias_score>
      <bias_analysis>The article presents a factual account of events surrounding Ukrainian President Zelensky's decision to cancel his trip to Saudi Arabia due to U.S.-Russia talks. The language used is neutral, but there is a subtle lean towards highlighting the diplomatic maneuvers and perspectives of the U.S. and Russia, as well as the involvement of other leaders like Erdogan and Trump. The article does not overtly criticize or praise any party, but the focus on the diplomatic efforts of the U.S. and Russia, as well as the mention of Trump's initiative, suggests a slight lean towards a right-leaning perspective. This is reflected in the balanced yet slightly favorable portrayal of the diplomatic actions taken by these countries and leaders.</bias_analysis>
    </article>
    <article>
      <url>https://www.breitbart.com/border/2025/02/19/mexico-hypes-up-minor-cartel-related-arrests-as-trump-highlights-their-inaction-on-drug-corruption/</url>
      <title>Mexico Hypes Up Minor Cartel-Related Arrests as Trump Highlights Their Inaction on Drug Corruption</title>
      <author>Breitbart News Foundation, Brandon Darby and Ildefonso Ortiz</author>
      <date>19-02-2025</date>
      <source>Breitbart News Network</source>
      <bias_score>3</bias_score>
      <bias_analysis>The article exhibits a right bias through its critical portrayal of the Mexican government's actions and its alignment with the Trump administration's perspective. The language used suggests skepticism towards Mexico's efforts, describing them as 'hyping up' minor arrests and seizures. The article emphasizes the Trump administration's stance and threats, presenting them as justified responses to Mexico's perceived inaction. The focus on corruption and the ineffectiveness of Mexican authorities further supports a narrative that aligns with conservative viewpoints, particularly those critical of foreign governments' handling of drug-related issues.</bias_analysis>
    </article>
    <article>
      <url>https://www.breitbart.com/europe/2025/02/19/president-trump-blasts-zelensky-a-dictator-without-elections/</url>
      <title>President Trump Blasts Zelensky: ‘A Dictator Without Elections’</title>
      <author>Nick Gilbertson</author>
      <date>19-02-2025</date>
      <source>Breitbart News Network</source>
      <bias_score>3.5</bias_score>
      <bias_analysis>The article exhibits a right bias, primarily due to its critical portrayal of Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky and the positive framing of Donald Trump's actions and statements. The language used by the author reflects a dismissive tone towards Zelensky, emphasizing Trump's criticisms and framing them as justified. The article also highlights Trump's efforts in negotiating peace, contrasting them with the perceived failures of other leaders, which aligns with a right-leaning perspective.</bias_analysis>
    </article>
    <article>
      <url>https://www.breitbart.com/politics/2025/02/19/white-house-bureaucrats-opposing-trumps-purge-undermine-democracy/</url>
      <title>White House: Bureaucrats Opposing Trump’s Purge Undermine Democracy</title>
      <author>Wendell Husebo</author>
      <date>19-02-2025</date>
      <source>Breitbart News Network</source>
      <bias_score>3</bias_score>
      <bias_analysis>The article exhibits a right bias through its supportive portrayal of President Trump's actions and its critical stance towards the media and bureaucrats opposing him. The language used by the author suggests a defense of Trump's efforts to dismantle the 'deep state,' framing these actions as democratic and aligning with the will of the people. The article also criticizes the media's portrayal of Trump's actions as a threat to democracy, suggesting that the media and Democrats are guilty of the accusations they levy against Trump. This presentation aligns with a right-leaning perspective, emphasizing support for Trump's administration and skepticism towards the media and bureaucratic opposition.</bias_analysis>
    </article>
    <article>
      <url>https://www.breitbart.com/politics/2025/02/19/trump-wants-congress-to-pass-agenda-in-one-big-beautiful-bill/</url>
      <title>Trump Wants Congress to Pass Agenda in ‘One Big Beautiful Bill’</title>
      <author>Nick Gilbertson</author>
      <date>19-02-2025</date>
      <source>Breitbart News Network</source>
      <bias_score>3</bias_score>
      <bias_analysis>The article exhibits a right bias through its favorable portrayal of Trump's legislative strategy and agenda. The language used is supportive of Trump's approach, emphasizing unity and effectiveness in Congress under his influence. The article presents Trump's plan as a positive and strategic move, aligning with conservative priorities such as border security and energy. The focus on Trump's 'America First Agenda' and the description of the legislative process as 'spectacular' and 'unbeatable' further indicate a positive bias towards Trump's policies and political strategy.</bias_analysis>
    </article>
    <article>
      <url>https://www.breitbart.com/politics/2025/02/19/watch-live-lori-chavez-deremer-confirmation-hearing-for-secretary-of-labor/</url>
      <title>Watch Live: Lori Chavez-DeRemer Confirmation Hearing for Secretary of Labor</title>
      <author>Breitbart News</author>
      <date>19-02-2025</date>
      <source>Breitbart News Network</source>
      <bias_score>2</bias_score>
      <bias_analysis>The article from Breitbart News presents a positive portrayal of Donald Trump's nominee, Lori Chavez-DeRemer, for Secretary of Labor. The language used in the article emphasizes her qualifications and the support she has from both the business community and labor unions, which aligns with a right-leaning perspective. The article does not present any critical viewpoints or opposing perspectives, focusing instead on the nominee's endorsements and the positive aspects of her nomination. This presentation style suggests a lean right bias.</bias_analysis>
    </article>
    <article>
      <url>https://www.breitbart.com/politics/2025/02/19/establishment-gop-senators-say-trump-is-saving-taxpayer-money-too-fast-demand-he-slow-down/</url>
      <title>Establishment GOP Senators Say Trump Is Saving Taxpayer Money ‘Too Fast,’ Demand He Slow Down</title>
      <author>Wendell Husebo</author>
      <date>19-02-2025</date>
      <source>Breitbart News Network</source>
      <bias_score>3.5</bias_score>
      <bias_analysis>The article exhibits a right bias through its portrayal of Trump's actions in a positive light, particularly in terms of his efforts to cut waste and purge the 'deep state.' The language used suggests support for Trump's aggressive approach to fulfilling campaign promises, while the concerns of establishment Republican senators are framed as obstacles to these efforts. The article also highlights the challenges Trump faces from political opponents, which further aligns with a narrative sympathetic to Trump and critical of his opposition. The overall tone and presentation suggest a favorable stance towards Trump's policies and actions, indicative of a right-leaning perspective.</bias_analysis>
    </article>
    <article>
      <url>https://www.breitbart.com/politics/2025/02/19/donald-trumps-gop-approval-rating-is-99-points-higher-than-mitch-mcconnells/</url>
      <title>Donald Trump’s GOP Approval Rating Is 99 Points Higher than Mitch McConnell’s</title>
      <author>Wendell Husebo</author>
      <date>19-02-2025</date>
      <source>Breitbart News Network</source>
      <bias_score>4</bias_score>
      <bias_analysis>The article exhibits a right bias, primarily due to its favorable portrayal of Donald Trump in contrast to Mitch McConnell. The author highlights Trump's high approval ratings among Republicans and frames McConnell as politically weakened and physically frail. The language used to describe McConnell, such as 'diminished power,' 'strange political situation,' and 'brink of political oblivion,' suggests a negative view of McConnell's influence and capabilities. The article emphasizes Trump's leadership and contrasts it with McConnell's perceived failures, aligning with a pro-Trump, right-leaning perspective.</bias_analysis>
    </article>
    <article>
      <url>https://www.breitbart.com/border/2025/02/19/trump-effect-migrant-border-encounters-drop-38-percent-from-bidens-last-full-month-in-office/</url>
      <title>TRUMP EFFECT: Migrant Border Encounters Drop 38 Percent from Biden’s Last Full Month in Office</title>
      <author>Bob Price</author>
      <date>19-02-2025</date>
      <source>Breitbart News Network</source>
      <bias_score>3</bias_score>
      <bias_analysis>The article exhibits a right bias, as it emphasizes the decrease in migrant border encounters following Donald Trump's inauguration, suggesting a positive correlation between his presidency and border control effectiveness. The language used is factual but highlights the differences between Trump's and Biden's administrations in a manner that favors Trump's policies. The focus on numerical data and comparisons serves to underscore the perceived success of Trump's approach to immigration, aligning with a right-leaning perspective.</bias_analysis>
    </article>
    <article>
      <url>https://www.breitbart.com/entertainment/2025/02/19/joy-behar-defends-maga-tom-hanks-saturday-night-live-sketch-made-anyone-who-voted-for-trump-look-like-a-racist/</url>
      <title>Joy Behar Defends MAGA: Tom Hanks’ ‘Saturday Night Live’ Sketch Made ‘Anyone Who Voted for Trump Look Like a Racist’</title>
      <author>Simon Kent</author>
      <date>19-02-2025</date>
      <source>Breitbart News Network</source>
      <bias_score>3</bias_score>
      <bias_analysis>The article exhibits a right bias, as it focuses on defending Trump supporters and criticizing Tom Hanks' portrayal of them on 'Saturday Night Live.' The language used suggests a negative view of the show and its portrayal of MAGA supporters, indicating a preference for conservative viewpoints. The article emphasizes the perceived injustice against Trump supporters and aligns with a narrative that critiques liberal media, which is characteristic of right-leaning perspectives.</bias_analysis>
    </article>
    <article>
      <url>https://www.breitbart.com/politics/2025/02/19/exclusive-jim-jordan-reveals-2025-priorities-on-rsc-podcast-with-host-ben-cline/</url>
      <title>Exclusive — Jim Jordan Reveals 2025 Priorities on RSC Podcast with Host Ben Cline</title>
      <author>Bradley Jaye</author>
      <date>19-02-2025</date>
      <source>Breitbart News Network</source>
      <bias_score>3</bias_score>
      <bias_analysis>The article exhibits a right bias due to its positive portrayal of Jim Jordan, the Republican Study Committee, and their alignment with Donald Trump's agenda. The language used is favorable towards conservative policies and figures, highlighting their efforts to promote national security, economic prosperity, and conservative values. The article also emphasizes the effectiveness of the Republican Study Committee's podcast in bypassing traditional media, which is presented as a strategic advantage. Overall, the article presents a clear perspective in favor of conservative politics and the Trump administration.</bias_analysis>
    </article>
    <article>
      <url>https://www.breitbart.com/europe/2025/02/19/trump-says-price-of-peace-may-be-fresh-ukrainian-elections-zelensky-accuses-president-of-disinformation/</url>
      <title>Trump Says Price of Peace May be Fresh Ukrainian Elections, Zelensky Accuses President of ‘Disinformation’</title>
      <author>Oliver JJ Lane</author>
      <date>19-02-2025</date>
      <source>Breitbart News Network</source>
      <bias_score>2.5</bias_score>
      <bias_analysis>The article exhibits a lean right bias. The author presents Trump's perspective on the Ukrainian situation in a manner that suggests sympathy with his viewpoint, emphasizing the need for fresh elections in Ukraine and portraying Zelensky in a negative light. The language used to describe Trump's actions and statements is generally neutral or supportive, while the portrayal of Zelensky and the Ukrainian government is more critical. The article also highlights the challenges faced by Ukraine in holding elections, but it does so in a way that aligns with Trump's narrative, suggesting a bias towards his stance.</bias_analysis>
    </article>
    <article>
      <url>https://www.breitbart.com/economy/2025/02/19/bloomberg-leading-indian-firm-cheats-visa-program-to-displace-middle-class-americans/</url>
      <title>Bloomberg: Lawsuits Say Indian Firm Cheated Visa Rules to Displace U.S. College Graduates</title>
      <author>Neil Munro</author>
      <date>19-02-2025</date>
      <source>Breitbart News Network</source>
      <bias_score>3.5</bias_score>
      <bias_analysis>The article presents a right-leaning bias, primarily through its critical portrayal of visa programs and their impact on American workers. The language used suggests a negative view of the visa system, emphasizing terms like 'fraud,' 'cheating,' and 'displacement' of U.S. workers. The article highlights the economic and political problems caused by these programs, aligning with a narrative that supports stricter immigration controls and prioritizes American workers. The focus on the negative consequences for U.S. graduates and the mention of political figures like Donald Trump in a favorable context further contribute to the right-leaning bias.</bias_analysis>
    </article>
    <article>
      <url>https://www.breitbart.com/politics/2025/02/19/exclusive-rep-chip-roy-introduces-bill-ending-crony-protections-for-covid-vaccine-manufacturers/</url>
      <title>Exclusive – Rep. Chip Roy Introduces Bill Ending Crony Protections for Covid Vaccine Manufacturers</title>
      <author>Bradley Jaye</author>
      <date>19-02-2025</date>
      <source>Breitbart News Network</source>
      <bias_score>3.5</bias_score>
      <bias_analysis>The article exhibits a right bias through its critical portrayal of COVID-19 vaccine manufacturers and federal mandates. The language used suggests skepticism towards the vaccines and the government's role in their distribution, framing the situation as a 'tragedy for healthcare freedom.' The article emphasizes the need for accountability and justice for those allegedly harmed by the vaccines, aligning with a conservative perspective that often prioritizes individual rights and skepticism of government intervention.</bias_analysis>
    </article>
    <article>
      <url>https://www.breitbart.com/europe/2025/02/19/trump-effect-denmark-announces-massive-rearmament-acknowledges-consequences-for-welfare-spending/</url>
      <title>Trump Effect: Denmark Announces ‘Massive’ Rearmament, Acknowledges ‘Consequences’ for Welfare Spending</title>
      <author>Kurt Zindulka</author>
      <date>19-02-2025</date>
      <source>Breitbart News Network</source>
      <bias_score>3</bias_score>
      <bias_analysis>The article exhibits a right bias through its framing and language choices. It presents the increase in Denmark's military spending as a positive outcome of Trump's influence on NATO, highlighting the need for European nations to take responsibility for their defense. The article emphasizes the perceived shortcomings of European countries in relying on U.S. defense support while maintaining welfare programs, aligning with a conservative perspective that prioritizes military spending over social welfare. The language used to describe Trump's impact and the necessity of military investment suggests a favorable view of his policies and a critical stance towards European reliance on American defense.</bias_analysis>
    </article>
    <article>
      <url>https://www.breitbart.com/politics/2025/02/19/exclusive-trump-agenda-in-works-key-subcommittee-holds-first-hearing-energy-policy-reducing-gas-prices-more/</url>
      <title>Exclusive — Trump Agenda in the Works as Key Subcommittee Holds First Hearing on Energy Policy, Reducing Gas Prices, and More</title>
      <author>Hannah Knudsen</author>
      <date>19-02-2025</date>
      <source>Breitbart News Network</source>
      <bias_score>3</bias_score>
      <bias_analysis>The article exhibits a right bias through its positive framing of Trump's energy agenda and the subcommittee's efforts to enact it. The language used is supportive of Trump's policies and critical of the previous administration's regulations, suggesting a partisan perspective. The article emphasizes the benefits of Trump's agenda and the subcommittee's commitment to reducing energy costs, portraying the efforts in a favorable light while implicitly criticizing the Biden administration's approach.</bias_analysis>
    </article>
    <article>
      <url>https://www.breitbart.com/entertainment/2025/02/19/biden-backer-george-clooney-shares-surprising-message-for-trump/</url>
      <title>Biden Backer George Clooney Shares Surprising Message for Trump</title>
      <author>Alana Mastrangelo</author>
      <date>19-02-2025</date>
      <source>Breitbart News Network</source>
      <bias_score>-2</bias_score>
      <bias_analysis>The article presents a generally neutral tone but leans slightly left due to its subtle framing and context. The author describes George Clooney's statements and actions in a way that emphasizes his Democratic background and his comments about democracy and political discourse. The language used is not overtly biased, but the choice to highlight Clooney's perspective and the context in which it is presented suggests a slight lean left. The article does not engage in strong language or overt criticism, maintaining a relatively balanced presentation overall.</bias_analysis>
    </article>
    <article>
      <url>https://www.breitbart.com/entertainment/2025/02/19/saturday-night-live-alum-victoria-jackson-slams-tom-hanks-over-racist-maga-skit/</url>
      <title>‘Saturday Night Live’ Alum Victoria Jackson Slams Tom Hanks over Racist MAGA Skit</title>
      <author>Alana Mastrangelo</author>
      <date>19-02-2025</date>
      <source>Breitbart News Network</source>
      <bias_score>3</bias_score>
      <bias_analysis>The article displays a right bias, primarily through its critical portrayal of Tom Hanks and the Saturday Night Live sketch. The language used in the article, such as 'racist Trump supporter sketch,' 'stupid,' and 'trite narrative,' suggests a negative view of the portrayal of MAGA supporters in the media. The article also highlights criticisms from right-leaning figures and emphasizes the idea that the show caters to 'snobbish liberal elites,' further indicating a right-leaning perspective. The author's choice of words and framing of the issue align with conservative viewpoints, contributing to the right bias rating.</bias_analysis>
    </article>
    <article>
      <url>https://www.breitbart.com/entertainment/2025/02/19/caught-with-his-pants-down-trump-hater-actor-mark-hamills-pants-appear-to-drop-during-bafta-speech/</url>
      <title>Caught with His Pants Down? Trump Hater Actor Mark Hamill’s Pants Appear to Drop During BAFTA Speech</title>
      <author>Alana Mastrangelo</author>
      <date>19-02-2025</date>
      <source>Breitbart News Network</source>
      <bias_score>1.5</bias_score>
      <bias_analysis>The article exhibits a lean right bias, primarily through its choice of language and focus. The author highlights Mark Hamill's criticism of Donald Trump, using phrases like 'incessantly disparages' to describe his actions, which suggests a negative view of Hamill's political stance. The article's tone appears to mock Hamill by emphasizing the embarrassing incident at the BAFTAs, rather than focusing on the event itself or Hamill's achievements. This choice of focus and language indicates a subtle preference against those who criticize Trump, aligning with a lean right perspective.</bias_analysis>
    </article>
    <article>
      <url>https://www.breitbart.com/entertainment/2025/02/19/watch-activists-protest-trump-at-the-kennedy-center-with-chants-and-interpretative-dance/</url>
      <title>Watch: Activists Protest Trump at the Kennedy Center With Chants and Interpretative Dance</title>
      <author>Alana Mastrangelo</author>
      <date>19-02-2025</date>
      <source>Breitbart News Network</source>
      <bias_score>2</bias_score>
      <bias_analysis>The article presents the protest against Trump at the Kennedy Center in a straightforward manner, but the choice of words like 'bizarre' and 'synchronized dance protest' suggests a subtle mocking tone towards the activists. The article also highlights Trump's role and statements in a neutral to slightly positive light, focusing on his new position and the financial challenges at the Kennedy Center. Overall, the language and presentation lean slightly towards a right bias, as it does not critically engage with Trump's actions or the concerns of the protesters.</bias_analysis>
    </article>
    <article>
      <url>https://www.breitbart.com/tech/2025/02/19/president-of-nyu-college-republicans-resigns-after-calling-barron-trump-an-oddity-on-campus/</url>
      <title>President of NYU College Republicans Resigns After Calling Barron Trump an ‘Oddity on Campus’</title>
      <author>Alana Mastrangelo</author>
      <date>19-02-2025</date>
      <source>Breitbart News Network</source>
      <bias_score>1</bias_score>
      <bias_analysis>The article presents a factual account of events surrounding the resignation of the NYU College Republicans president, Kaya Walker, after comments about Barron Trump. The language used is straightforward and does not exhibit strong bias. However, the article does provide a platform for Walker's perspective, including her regret and defense of her comments, which could be seen as slightly sympathetic to her situation. Additionally, the mention of the College Republicans' support for Trump and the invitation to Barron Trump aligns with conservative values, giving the article a slight lean to the right.</bias_analysis>
    </article>
    <article>
      <url>https://www.breitbart.com/tech/2025/02/19/leftist-echo-chamber-reddit-allows-viral-posts-calling-for-repeat-of-french-revolution/</url>
      <title>Leftist Echo Chamber Reddit Allows Viral Posts Calling for Repeat of French Revolution</title>
      <author>Alana Mastrangelo</author>
      <date>19-02-2025</date>
      <source>Breitbart News Network</source>
      <bias_score>4</bias_score>
      <bias_analysis>The article exhibits a right bias, as it portrays Reddit and leftists in a negative light, using terms like 'leftist echo chamber' and 'censorship of conservatives.' The language suggests that the platform is unfairly targeting conservatives while allowing violent rhetoric from the left. The article also implies that the left's actions are hypocritical and dictatorial, contrasting them with President Trump's actions, which are framed as being unfairly criticized. This framing and choice of language indicate a clear preference for conservative viewpoints and a critical stance towards the left.</bias_analysis>
    </article>
    <article>
      <url>https://www.breitbart.com/sports/2025/02/18/christian-girls-basketball-team-forced-to-compete-against-transgender-player-as-california-defies-trump-order/</url>
      <title>Christian Girls Basketball Team Forced to Compete Against Transgender Player As California Defies Trump Order</title>
      <author>Paul Bois</author>
      <date>18-02-2025</date>
      <source>Breitbart News Network</source>
      <bias_score>3</bias_score>
      <bias_analysis>The article displays a right bias through its framing and language choices. It highlights the defiance of California against a Trump executive order, suggesting a negative view of the state's actions. The mention of 'forced to compete' implies a lack of agency for the Christian girls' basketball team, which can be interpreted as a critique of policies supporting transgender athletes. The article also emphasizes the involvement of the Trump administration's Department of Education in investigating the situation, which aligns with a narrative supportive of Trump's policies. Overall, the language and presentation favor a conservative perspective, focusing on the perceived conflict between state actions and federal directives.</bias_analysis>
    </article>
    <article>
      <url>https://www.breitbart.com/politics/2025/02/18/exclusive-trump-white-house-officials-to-take-star-turn-at-cpac-the-new-generation-of-maga-leaders/</url>
      <title>Exclusive — Trump White House Officials to Take Star Turn at CPAC: ‘The New Generation of MAGA Leaders’</title>
      <author>Matthew Boyle</author>
      <date>18-02-2025</date>
      <source>Breitbart News Network</source>
      <bias_score>4</bias_score>
      <bias_analysis>The article exhibits a right bias due to its positive portrayal of former President Trump and his administration. It emphasizes the influence and effectiveness of Trump's team, describing them as 'impressive' and 'energetic,' and highlights their achievements and strategic prowess. The language used is supportive and admiring, focusing on the successes and impact of Trump's leadership and his team's role in advancing conservative policies. The article lacks critical analysis or opposing viewpoints, reinforcing a favorable narrative towards Trump and his associates.</bias_analysis>
    </article>
    <article>
      <url>https://www.breitbart.com/clips/2025/02/18/trump-musk-wont-be-involved-in-things-that-pertain-to-his-businesses/</url>
      <title>Trump: Musk Won’t Be Involved in Things that Pertain to His Businesses</title>
      <author>Ian Hanchett</author>
      <date>18-02-2025</date>
      <source>Breitbart News Network</source>
      <bias_score>0</bias_score>
      <bias_analysis>The article presents a straightforward account of a discussion between President Donald Trump and Elon Musk regarding potential conflicts of interest related to Musk's businesses. The author's language is neutral and factual, focusing on the content of the conversation without inserting any subjective opinions or emotionally charged language. The article does not exhibit any clear bias towards either political side, as it simply reports on the interaction and statements made by Trump and Musk.</bias_analysis>
    </article>
    <article>
      <url>https://www.breitbart.com/clips/2025/02/18/bessent-tariffs-could-bring-substantial-revenue-but-we-use-them-for-other-purposes-as-well/</url>
      <title>Bessent: Tariffs ‘Could Bring’ Substantial Revenue, But We Use Them for Other Purposes As Well</title>
      <author>Ian Hanchett</author>
      <date>18-02-2025</date>
      <source>Breitbart News Network</source>
      <bias_score>2</bias_score>
      <bias_analysis>The article presents a perspective that is generally supportive of the use of tariffs as a tool for revenue generation and trade negotiation, aligning with policies associated with former President Trump. The language used is neutral and factual, focusing on the potential benefits of tariffs without delving into potential negative impacts or criticisms. This suggests a lean towards a right-leaning bias, as it highlights the positive aspects of a policy typically favored by conservative politics without presenting counterarguments or critical viewpoints.</bias_analysis>
    </article>
    <article>
      <url>https://www.breitbart.com/clips/2025/02/18/dem-rep-crockett-trump-and-musk-are-idiots-no-one-should-have-confidence-in-the-administration/</url>
      <title>Dem Rep. Crockett: Trump and Musk ‘Are Idiots’ — No One Should Have Confidence in the Administration</title>
      <author>Pam Key</author>
      <date>18-02-2025</date>
      <source>Breitbart News Network</source>
      <bias_score>-6</bias_score>
      <bias_analysis>The article exhibits a left bias due to its negative portrayal of Donald Trump and Elon Musk, using derogatory language such as 'idiots' to describe them. The author's tone is dismissive and critical, particularly towards the administration and its actions. The language used suggests a strong disapproval of the figures mentioned, aligning with a left-leaning perspective.</bias_analysis>
    </article>
    <article>
      <url>https://www.breitbart.com/clips/2025/02/18/bessent-id-like-deficit-as-share-of-gdp-to-have-3-in-front-of-it-by-2028/</url>
      <title>Bessent: I’d Like Deficit as Share of GDP to Have ‘3 In Front of It’ ‘by 2028’</title>
      <author>Ian Hanchett</author>
      <date>18-02-2025</date>
      <source>Breitbart News Network</source>
      <bias_score>1.5</bias_score>
      <bias_analysis>The article leans right due to its focus on fiscal conservatism and the emphasis on making the 2017 tax cuts permanent, which aligns with Republican economic policies. The language used by the author is neutral and factual, but the choice of content and framing around reducing the deficit through spending cuts and maintaining tax cuts reflects a conservative perspective. The article does not present opposing viewpoints or critique the proposed policies, which further indicates a lean right bias.</bias_analysis>
    </article>
    <article>
      <url>https://www.breitbart.com/politics/2025/02/18/trump-orders-all-remaining-biden-appointed-u-s-attorneys-to-be-terminated/</url>
      <title>Trump Orders ‘All Remaining’ Biden-Appointed U.S. Attorneys to Be Terminated</title>
      <author>Elizabeth Weibel</author>
      <date>18-02-2025</date>
      <source>Breitbart News Network</source>
      <bias_score>3</bias_score>
      <bias_analysis>The article exhibits a right bias through its supportive portrayal of Trump's actions and decisions. The language used suggests a positive framing of Trump's decision to terminate Biden-appointed U.S. attorneys, emphasizing the need to 'clean house' and restore confidence in the justice system. The article also highlights the politicization of the Department of Justice under Biden, aligning with a narrative that favors Trump's perspective and actions. The choice of words and the focus on Trump's rationale for his actions contribute to the article's right-leaning bias.</bias_analysis>
    </article>
  </articles>
</articles_search_results>
